Are you looking at naked tribeswomen?
你在看原住民裸女嗎？
No,look.
不是，你看
That's a pig.
這是豬耶
I know. But look at the knobs on it!
我知道，你看它的咪咪多大
嘿
Emily's cousin kicked me out.
艾蜜莉的表妹 竟然把我趕出來
-What? -Why?
什麼？ 為什麼？
When you sublet from your wife's cousin...
跟老婆的表妹分租公寓
...then you divorce,sometimes the cousin wants his apartment back.
要是之後又離婚 表妹就會突然把房子要回去
Didn't you sign a lease?
怎麼可以？你們沒簽約嗎？
Who needs a lease when it's "family"?
誰跟親戚租公寓還簽約？
You can stay with us.
你可以跟我們住
Anything you need.
包在我們身上
But you have to let us know when you feel better...
你心情好一點就說一聲
...so we can make fun of your hair.
好讓我們取笑你的雞窩頭
You got it.
沒問題
Thanks,I really appreciate this. I'm going to get packing again.
謝謝你們，我太感激了
我得回去打包行李了
I've been moving around so much that I feel like a nomad.
我最近不斷搬家 簡直像是遊民
-What? -He thought you said gonad.
怎麼了？他以為你說的是「咪咪」
The One Where Ross Moves ln
本集播出：「自找苦吃」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
If every place were this clean, it'd be tough making a living.
要是每家餐廳都跟你的一樣乾淨
我就沒飯吃了
Oh,Larry!
別說了，賴瑞
Do health inspectors work on commission?
衛生稽查員收佣金嗎？
No,bribes.
不，不過收紅包
-It's okay to laugh? -I was just kidding.
我可以笑吧？當然，我開玩笑啦
-I'll check the kitchen floor. -Knock yourself out.
我去檢查廚房地板 請自便，賴瑞
I don't get violations. You could eat beans off that floor.
我絕對不會違規
地板乾淨到 豆子都能撿起來吃
But don't,because that'd be a violation.
別吃喔，否則你就違規了
Yummy!
真可口
Yeah,I'd let him check out my kitchen floor.
你說賴瑞？我也願意讓他檢查我廚房地板
A ninety-eight.
98分
I deducted two points for not wearing your hat.
你沒戴帽子所以扣兩分
That is a Section 5 violation.
因為違反第五條規定
Now look,Larry,honey.
賴瑞，親愛的
I wrote the book on Section 5.
第五條條文我是專家
You only need to wear it in the kitchen.
在廚房才要戴帽子
-Where's your hat? -ln the kitchen. I'll get it.
你的帽子呢？
在廚房，我進去拿
There's the two points!
扣兩分
You should really read that book you wrote.
專家也不過如此嘛
You saw the hat in the kitchen and knew she'd go in hatless to get it.
你看到帽子在廚房
知道她進去時沒戴帽子
You could have your own health inspector detective show.
你可以當衛生稽查員 兼偵探了
I don't know about that.
你太客氣了
But then I could be your sidekick,Voonda.
我可以演你的助手薇達
Maybe I could ask Voonda to dinner sometime?
薇達可以留電話給我 我就能約她出去吃飯
She would love that...
她一定很開心
...since you know all the clean places to eat.
因為你知道哪家餐廳才衛生
I'll call you.
我再打給你 好
He's so funny!
他真幽默
「中央咖啡館」
Thank you.
謝了 謝謝
How's Ross doing since all the Emily stuff?
羅斯還好吧？ 還在為艾蜜莉傷心嗎？
He's not great.
心情不太好
But he's dealing with it. Wait,you're not
不過還死不了 等等，你該不會…
拜託，不可能
I can't get started with all that Ross stuff again.
我不可能再跟羅斯交往
He'll be screwed up for a long time.
他還要失魂落魄大半年哩
Besides,I don't go for guys right after they get divorced.
況且你也知道 我不喜歡剛離婚的男人
Right,you only go for them five minutes before they get married.
對，快結婚的人你才要
-Two pounds of mocha java. -It's Danny.
我要兩磅爪哇摩卡咖啡 是丹尼
Are you going to go out again?
你們還會出去嗎？
I don't know. He hasn't called since we went out.
不知道 上次出去一次之後 他就沒再打給我
I see him in the hallway. We flirt. I'm all:
我們只在走廊上打情罵俏
我笑得花枝亂顫
And then nothing.
卻沒下文
嘿
Wow,thirsty.
你很渴吧？
I'm having a party on Saturday. Sort of a housewarming thing.
我週六要辦派對 慶祝我搬新家
-Fun. -Great!
真有意思 真好
I'm looking forward to it.
我也希望週六趕快到
See you!
那我走了
So I guess we won't be warming his house.
看來他新家不歡迎我們
All right,I see what he's doing.
很好，我知道他在玩什麼把戲
He's not asking me out because he wants me to ask him out.
他故意不約我 因為他要我主動約他
And you won't do that.
可是你不鳥他
That's right!
沒錯
Because that would give him the control.
否則主導權就落在他手裡
So now he comes up with this "I've got a party" thing...
他現在故意說什麼要辦派對
...to get me to hint for an invitation.
要我暗示他約我
Blew up in his face,didn't it?
可是我當場給他好看
So there is no party?
所以他根本沒有要辦派對
No,there's a party. There's a party.
有，當然有
But the power?
不過誰是老大
That is still up for grabs.
還不知道哩
You follow me?
你聽得懂嗎？
I think so.
應該吧
So he won't invite you to his party because he likes you?
你說他喜歡你 所以故意不約你
Exactly!
就是這樣
Then why didn't he invite me?
可是他為什麼不約我？
To throw me off.
故意吊我胃口
羅斯
Hey,roomies!
親愛的室友
I love what you've done with the place.
你把家裡佈置得真溫馨
I know it's a lot of boxes.
我知道箱子堆得到處都是
-I appreciate you letting me stay here.
-Not a problem.
我要再次感謝你們收容我 沒問題
Since you'll be here a while...
既然你要在這裡住一陣子
...we could put your name on the answering machine.
乾脆錄一段你的留言
I hope you don't mind...
是啊 希望你們別介意
...but I kind of already jazzed it up a little.
我已經錄了一段
Check it out.
你們聽
We will
我們一定
We will call you back
一定會回你電話
Pretty cool.
很酷吧？
-You're fake laughing too,right? -The tears are real.
你也是假笑吧？不過眼淚是真的
You look beautiful this evening.
你今晚真漂亮
Show me the badge again.
再給我看一次徽章
Shiny.
真是閃閃發亮
You mind if I wash up? Who knows where these have been?
我去洗個手
誰曉得這兩個寶貝碰過什麼
You are just nonstop!
你真是寶到不行
-We're out of here. -Why?
我們必須立刻走 為什麼？
I saw 1 0 violations. I'm shutting this place down!
我剛經過廚房就看到十項違規
我要勒令他們停業
-You have the power to do that? -This does.
你辦得到嗎？ 有這個就可以
Shut it down.
那就讓他們停業吧
嘿
What are you doing?
你做什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼
You built a fort,didn't you?
你造了一個城堡？
Kind of.
差不多
Oh,my God! The air purifier. Ross' air purifier.
天啊，是他的空氣清淨器
All I heard for four years through college was....
我大學四年只聽得到…
You should have gone out once in a while.
老兄，你不該只悶在宿舍裡
-I hate this thing! -Come on,Chandler.
我討厭這東西
錢德
Ross is our friend. He needs us right now.
羅斯是我們的好友 他現在需要我們幫忙
So why don't you be a grownup and come watch TV in the fort?
成熟點，進來城堡看電視吧
Can't believe that Larry closed down Churman's. I love that place.
賴瑞竟然勒令楚門餐廳停業
我很喜歡那家餐廳
You should have heard about all their violations.
你應該聽聽他們有哪些違規
Larry said that they should call it Vermin's.
賴瑞說他們該改名蟑螂餐廳
That guy just plain kills me.
那傢伙實在太耍寶了
I wanted to invite you to the party.
我來請你們參加明晚的派對
Thanks,I'll try to stop by.
謝了，我們有時間就過去
Actually,I think I'm going to be busy.
不過我可能有事
You are?
是嗎？
Remember,I've got that gala?
對，我上次跟你說要參加比賽
What's the gala for?
什麼比賽？
It's a regatta gala.
賽船會
Do you sail?
你會開帆船？
No,but I support it.
不會，可是我贊助比賽
I hope I see you tomorrow night. Take care.
好吧，明晚見咯 保重，再見
Walked right into that one, didn't he?
我這招打得他滿臉豆花
What one?
哪一招？
You wanted him to invite you and he did.
你希望他邀你參加派對 他也來啦
He waited until the last minute. So if I said yes...
可是他等到最後一刻才來 如果我答應
...he'd know I had nothing better to do than wait for his invitation.
他就知道 我沒事可做等著去他家
But I said no...
但是我說不去
...which puts me back in the driver's seat.
所以還是我佔上風
So the ball is in his court?
正點，所以換他出招咯？
Ball?
出招？
No,there's no ball.
他沒招可出了
Hey,Phoebe,you want to join us?
菲比，你吃不吃？
-Oh,sure,yeah. Where is this from? -It's from Sun Ling's.
好啊，哪裡買的？ 三林餐廳
Oh,Larry just told me something about Sun Ling.
賴瑞跟我提過三林中菜
Oh,no,thank you.
算了，多謝
Joey,please.
喬伊，麻煩你
Sorry.
對不起
Hello,children.
小鬼們
You want to play some foosball? Please?
要不要玩桌足球？求求你？
好吧 不…
We moved the table into my room because of all the boxes.
遊戲桌搬進我房間了
因為外面太多箱子
Come on!
進來吧
I have one question.
我有個問題
What is the deal with this?
這是什麼碗糕？
Bye-bye,little puppet Joey hand?
小布偶喬伊說再見？
No,the quiet down thing.
不是，叫我閉嘴的手勢
You mean this.
你是說這樣啊
I don't know how much more I can take.
我不知道我還能憋多久
Did you know he taped over my Baywatch tape with a show about bugs?
他竟然拿我的海灘遊俠錄影帶 去錄什麼怪小蟲
My God!
What if that had been porn?
要是裡面錄的是A片呢？
All right,this may be tough...
別激動，或許你憋得很難過
...but it's Ross. I survived college with him.
可是他是老友羅斯
我跟他大學住四年都沒死了
I guess I can hold out a little longer.
我或許還可以再忍一陣子
Let's have a game.
來玩吧 好
不要… 萬歲
Fellas?
兩位
So he's out of here.
他非走不可
Got anything to eat? I went to Jono's and it was closed.
這裡有沒有東西可吃？
我剛去強諾買雞塊 那裡竟然停業了
I took Larry there,but it was all violated,so we shut it down.
我帶賴瑞去，餐廳不合規定 我們勒令他們停業
If this guy keeps closing our favorite places,where will we eat?
菲比，這傢伙不斷關掉 大家喜歡去的餐館 以後我們上哪吃飯？
I don't know. Clean places?
不曉得，乾淨的地方？
Yum!
It's Danny.
是丹尼
Don't let him in! I'm supposed to be at a gala.
別讓他進來，我現在 應該去看帆船賽了
We'll be right there. Can't you say it's later?
我們馬上過去 不能說大賽還沒開始嗎？
What kind of a regatta gala starts at night?
什麼？哪種帆船在晚上比賽？
The fake kind.
假的那種
-I need a ladle. You got a ladle? -We have a ladle.
嗨，我想借個勺子，你有嗎？
我們有
See you at the party.
謝了，待會兒見 好
You know what Larry would say? He'd say,"See you ladle."
你們知道賴瑞會怎麼回答嗎？ 他會說，「杓後見」
I'm done. You want anything? Sports? International?
我看完了，你要看嗎，羅斯？ 有體育、國際
Apartment listings?
租屋版
I'll take sports.
我要體育版
Mine!
我要
All right,international.
那就國際版好了
That's mine too.
我也要
I'm ltalian.
我是意大利裔
I could check apartment listings, though there's never anything here.
不然看看租屋廣告吧 不過報上向來沒吉屋
Not even on page seven?
第7頁也沒有嗎？
You're right. Here's an affordable place.
有耶，你說得對 有個地方價錢很公道
Two-bedroom,close to work. It's available in five weeks.
兩房、上班也近 可是還要五周才能搬進去
What about that circled one?
圈起來那個呢？
It's kind of expensive for a studio.
不知道耶，就套房來說有點貴
But it's available now.
可是現在就能搬進去
Isn't it?
對不對？
Yes,it is.
的確是
Let's go look at it!
我們去看看
There we go!
好，我們走 走吧
Guys,would you chip in for some new air filters for the purifier?
對了，忘了告訴你們
可不可以大家分攤買濾芯？
I mean,after all, we are all using it.
畢竟空氣清淨器大家都有用到
Let's go quicker!
快點走 好
Oh,my God!
天啊
Look at this kitchen/bathroom.
你們看這個廚房…兼浴室
That's great! So you can cook while in the tub.
太棒了，可以一邊煮飯 一邊洗澡
Somebody was using his head.
房東真是太聰明了
Let's check out the rest of the place.
再看看其他地方
I think this is it.
就這麼大了
I don't know. Maybe we should keep looking.
我們應該看看別間公寓
But this place is available now.
可是這地方馬上就能搬進來
You don't want to be stuck with us for five weeks.
對啊，你不會願意 繼續跟我們住五周
So you think I should take this place?
你覺得我應該租下？
It's perfect!
這裡很棒啊
How about you?
你呢？
Kitchen,slash,bathroom.
這裡有廚房兼浴室耶
I see what you guys are saying.
好吧，我懂了
I'll go downstairs and fill out an application.
我下樓填申請表
We are bad people.
我們是壞人
He knew we were trying to get rid of him.
他知道我們想趕他走
Could we get a bathtub in our kitchen?
我們廚房能不能裝浴缸？
Ready for dinner?
要去吃飯了嗎？
-Absolutely. -Great.
好啊
You wanted to go to the ltalian place on Bleecker St.?
你上次不是說要去布裡克街 那家意大利餐廳？
I love that place!
我愛死那裡了
So,no.
所以…不行
How about Mama Lozetti's?
「李賽提老媽」呢？
Sure.
沒問題
How long has that milk been sitting out?
不知道那瓶牛奶放多久了？
No,this place is totally healthy.
這地方非常乾淨
This milk is mine. I bought this today...
那瓶牛奶是我的 今天買的
...because I was thirsty for milk, you know?
我突然想喝牛奶
Okay,let's go.
我們走吧
Hey,buddy.
老兄
Health Code 1 1 B requires that refuse be taken out the back exit.
你知道衛生規則 11條B款嗎？ 垃圾應該從後門拿出去
But then I have to go all the way around.
可是這樣就得從乾洗店繞路
So you choose convenience over health?
你寧可方便也不顧衛生？
Would you be interested in a free coffee?
請你喝咖啡好嗎？
Stop,Larry.
賴瑞，別這樣
Can't you just be Larry and not Larry the health inspector guy?
你能不能別老想著工作？
It was exciting at first.
一開始還很刺激
But now,it's like,so where are we going to eat ever?
現在簡直哪家餐廳也去不了
I suppose I could give him a warning.
不然我口頭警告他好了
Thank you.
謝謝
Go,go!
快走啊
If,after dinner, you still need to bust someone...
要是吃飽飯後你還想抓人
...I know a hot dog vendor who picks his nose.
我知道哪個熱狗攤老闆 喜歡挖鼻子
Maybe we did good, helping Ross get back on his feet.
搞不好我們做的是好事 幫助羅斯早點恢復正常
That was a nice place.
況且那地方實在不錯 是啊
No closet space,but he could hang his stuff out the window in a bag.
雖然櫃子不多 不過可以用袋子裝好掛在窗外
是啊
What do we do?
現在該怎麼辦？
I don't know.
不知道
Maybe pizza?
要吃披薩嗎？
About Ross!
我說的是羅斯
喂
It's the apartment manager. Ross put us as references.
我是，是公寓經理 羅斯填我們當介紹人
Ross is the greatest guy. He's very reliable
羅斯絕對是好人 這人非常可靠
Of course,he has a big,huge dog that barks into the night.
不過他養了一支大狗 那支狗半夜叫個不停
Well,who doesn't love dogs?
誰不喜歡狗？
He's a tap dancer.
他是個踢踏舞者
Yes,some would say that is a lost art.
這的確是失傳的藝術
He's a pimp!
他是皮條客
There you go. He's a pimp.
沒錯，就是皮條客
He's a big,tap-dancing pimp!
他是會跳踢踏舞的皮條客
喂
-Okay,honey,I'm ready. -What are you doing?
我準備好了 你穿這樣幹麼？
I am going to wander into the party and I will be all,you know:
我要晃進派對 裝做一副
"l don't need this, I'm coming from a regatta gala."
剛從帆船賽回來的樣子
Did you get this out of a book?
你這是從書上學來的嗎？
Monica,honey,this is as real as it gets.
親愛的摩妮卡，書如人生啊
This is never going to work. He's right there.
該死，這可不行 他就站在那裡
Just go say hi.
去打聲招呼就行啦
I have to go downstairs and back up, as if I'm coming home from the gala.
不行，我得從樓下走上來 假裝我剛從外面回來
So just go distract him. But don't be sexy.
你去引開他的注意力 但是別勾引他
丹尼
What's going on?
你好
This is a great party. Great food.
這個派對真不錯，食物也很好
You know,most parties,it's all chips and salsa,chips and salsa.
大部分派對都只有薯片、辣醬 薯片、辣醬
So....
What's this?
這是什麼？
Salad.
沙拉
喔
And what's this?
這又是什麼？
Bread.
麵包
Aren't you a chef?
你不是廚師嗎？
嘿，瑞秋
Right,tonight was your party.
對了，你今晚要辦派對
You look great! I'm glad you made it.
你穿得真漂亮 幸好你趕回來了
Well,you know, the gala had to end sometime.
比賽總不能沒完沒了
Don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
你別走開，我馬上回來
沒問題
Whose court is the ball in now?
你說現在換誰出招啦？
I thought there wasn't a ball.
你不是說他沒招可出？
Come on. He's glad I came. He doesn't want me to go anywhere.
拜託，他很高興我來了 而且還叫我別走開
Ball's flying all over the place.
我們兩個現在是你來我往
This is my friend,Tom.
瑞秋，這是我朋友湯姆
This is the girl I told you about.
這就是我跟你提過的小姐
Come on! You telling people about me?
拜託，你跟人提過我？
I think you two could really hit it off.
你們一定會來電
I'm gonna go mingle.
我去跟朋友哈拉了
So you work at Bloomingdale's? My mom calls it "Bloomies."
你在布魯明代爾百貨上班？
我媽都說那裡是「布明兒」
At ease,soldier!
真不錯，稍息，大兵
I'm sorry?
什麼？
You can just drop the act. I know what's going on.
沒關係，湯姆，你別裝了 我知道你們搞什麼鬼
You're Danny's wingman,right?
你是丹尼的好友對不對？
You guys are best buds,frat bros.
你們交情老、感情好
I'm going to go talk to a friend.
我要去…找朋友
Yeah,you go talk to your friend.
請便，去找你朋友吧
Go tell him,"Nice try."
告訴他，「這招漂亮」
He just keeps lobbing them up...
他真是出招連連
...and I keep knocking them right out of the park.
不過我可是招招都破
I think I need a drink.
我想喝杯飲料 我也要
Ninety-eight...
98、
...ninety-nine...
99、
...one hundred!
Okay. Go.
走吧
Dude,I'm telling you,I'm fine.
告訴你，我沒問題
Here we go,here we go.
我扶住你了
嘿 嘿
So I didn't get that apartment. Some problem with my application.
我沒租到那間公寓 我的申請作業出狀況
You're kidding?
哪有可能？ 不會吧
But Phoebe said I could stay at her place for a while,so....
不過菲比答應讓我搬去跟她住
Well,you can't stay with Phoebe. We're roomies.
你不能住菲比家 我們可是室友耶
You don't need me taking up all your space.
我不能再佔用你們公寓
We got plenty of space. There's still some by that speaker.
反正這裡大得很 音箱旁邊還有空地
Please,just stay.
住下來吧 對
Are you sure?
你們確定？ 當然
-Definitely. -You have to stay.
羅斯，你非住下來不可
好吧 就這麼辦
So I'm a pimp,huh?
你們說我是皮條客？
It's okay.
算了
Sometimes I can be a pain in the ass.
我知道我有時候很顧人怨
But just talk to me. Tell me if something bothers you.
不過你們可以直說 明白告訴我哪裡做得不好
And I'll do everything I can to keep my annoying habits just....
我可以盡量改掉惹人嫌的習慣
Well,I see you've had a very productive day.
顯然你今天過得很充實
The cowboy hat's a little much.
不過戴牛仔帽也太扯了吧？
Come on,it's fun!
進來一起玩
All right.
好吧
Isn't this a woman's hat?
這不是女人的帽子嗎？
Stop talking crazy,and make us tea!
還不趕快閉嘴去泡茶？